Hello everyone, welcome back to English
POD, my name is Marco and I'm Erica and
we're bringing you another great elementary
lesson for all those elementary learners.
In today's lesson we've
got some excellent language
that will help you to describe
someone's appearance.
It's something that everyone has
learned before in school, describing
people, so we're going to review
that and give you some better phrases.
Some real English phrases.
Real English phrases.
Ok, great, so let's listen
to our dialogue for the
first time and then we'll
come back and talk about it.
I heard you were in a day
last night, so how did it go?
I went all the juicy details.
Um, well, actually, we had a fantastic
time last night. He was amazing.
Ok, now you really have to fill me in. What's
he like? He's really good looking. He's quite
tall around 6'1", he's in his early 30s, and
he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
He sounds hard! What
does he do for a living?
You know what?
This is the best part.
David is a junior
investment banker at Fortune
Bank, so he's got a great
career path ahead of him.
Hold on a sec. His name is David, yeah?
That's my brother!
Alright, so interesting dialogue.
Small world.
It is a small world. I don't know how I
would feel about dating my friend's brother.
Really?
No, I wouldn't feel good about it. Why?
Oh, because if you break up
with the brother, then that means
you'll have to end the
friendship with your best friend.
Maybe. Dangerous. Girls are
more complicated with that.
We're not that complicated.
Well, you know what? Let's look at
the language before this gets too far.
Alright, let's take a look
at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Language takeaway today
will bring you three words.
The first one is
heard, heard, heard.
So you guys know this word.
Past tense of here, right? Right.
But the way it's used
is quite interesting.
Let's listen to a couple of
examples of how it's used.
Example one.
I heard you're dating a new guy.
Example two.
Julie told me she heard
that you're pregnant.
Example three.
What? You got fired? I heard that you quit.
So when you say for example,
oh, I heard you were pregnant.
Oh, this is like telling someone
that you found some information
about them, but you're not
sure if it's true or if it's false.
Okay. Our next word, fill me in.
Fill me in.
Fill me in. Fill me in.
So when you tell someone to fill
you in, you're saying tell me about it.
Tell me the details. I could
say, I'm sorry I was late
for the meeting. Can you
fill me in on what happened?
Exactly. Or I could say, I missed the first
five minutes of the movie. Fill me in.
Exactly. Okay, great word.
And our last phrase today, career path.
Career path, career path, career path.
So what's a career path?
I guess this is the plan for your
job over several like 10 or 20 years.
Right. All the different jobs and
things you do during your career.
Yeah. That's your career path.
So in this case, David has a
really good career path because
he's going to be a really rich
and powerful investment banker.
Yes. So career path.
Very good. So now let's listen
to our dialogue again and pay
special attention to the
language used to describe David.
Because when we come back,
we're going to talk about this.
Irene, I heard you were
on a date last night.
So how did it go?
I won all the juicy details.
Well, actually, we had a
fantastic time last night.
He was amazing.
Okay. Now you really have to fill me in.
What's he like?
He's really good looking.
He's quite tall around six one.
He's in his early 30s and he's got
the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
He sounds hot.
What does he do for a living?
You know what?
This is the best part.
David is a junior investment
banker at Fortune Bank.
So he's got a great
career path ahead of him.
Hold on, Asick.
His name is David. Yeah.
That's my brother.
So we found some really great words
and phrases used to describe someone.
Exactly. There's a lot of language in
here talking about the way someone looks.
So let's listen again as
Irene describes David.
He's really good looking.
He's quite tall around six one.
He's in his early 30s and he's got
the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
He's really good looking.
He's quite tall around six one.
He's in his early 30s and he's got
the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
Okay, so let's break this down.
The first thing she says
is he's really good looking.
Good looking. Good looking. Good looking.
So good looking is the equivalent
of handsome or pretty pretty.
Yeah, good looking.
But I think good looking sounds
a lot more natural than handsome.
Yeah, you wouldn't really use handsome.
I'd like I would never say that.
Even though it's correct, it's just good
looking sounds much more natural.
I guess for me, whenever someone says
handsome, it sounds like an older person.
Yeah, it sounds old for my grandma.
Exactly, handsome young man.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay.
Now let's look at the next thing she said.
He's quite tall.
Quite tall.
So we know quite means very.
Yeah.
And tall, we know.
Right.
So you can describe a
person in different ways.
He's quite tall.
He's kind of tall.
He's sort of tall.
He's a bit short.
He's not that short.
Yeah.
Okay.
So these are great words we can
use to describe someone's height.
Okay.
Then she talked about his exact height.
Yes.
Right.
She said he was 6'1".
6'1".
Around 6'1".
Yeah.
This is interesting because
in the United States
and Canada, you give a person's
height using feet and inches.
That's right.
Right.
So we don't talk about
meters and centimeters.
Right.
So 6'1" would be 6'1".
Exactly.
So in other countries, you would
talk about centimeters or meters.
So 6'1" is like 6'1" is about 180.
Yeah.
But that... So this is an
interesting difference between...
Like English speaking countries
and European countries.
Right.
Okay.
So the next time you give
your height to someone,
make sure you do it
in feet more or less.
It sounds a lot more natural.
And actually, if you say to
somebody in Canada, for example, I'm
175 centimeters, they wouldn't
know really how tall that was.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, the next part
is really, really useful.
She said he's in his early 30s.
In his early 30s.
His early 30s.
Early 30s.
So this is a way of
describing someone's age
without actually giving
the exact number.
Exactly.
So for example, early 30s.
So like 32, 33, mid 30s.
Like 34 or 35?
36.
Oh, 36.
Yeah.
And then late 30s would be 38, 39.
And you could do the same
thing for like 40s, 40s, 50s, 60s, 20s.
20s, right?
Starting at 20s.
You wouldn't do that.
You wouldn't do this before your 20s.
I don't think it's really common
to talk about your teens.
Right.
You can say like his
mid teens or early teens.
Yeah.
Sounds a bit weird.
Okay.
Great language used to describe people.
But one more word.
Right.
He's hot.
Or he sounds hot.
Yeah.
He's hot.
So this is another
sort of informal way of
describing someone
who's really good looking.
Good looking.
Really sexy.
Right.
It could be girl or boy.
She's hot.
Yeah.
But it is informal.
It is really informal.
Maybe even a little bit offensive.
You wouldn't go up to a
girl and say, wow, you're hot.
No.
It's a little bit into impolite.
Right.
You would say, wow, you're
really pretty or you're gorgeous.
Yeah.
But you wouldn't say, wow.
No.
You would never say that to somebody.
Right.
That's something you would
comment with your friends.
Okay.
So we've looked at some really
good language for describing people.
Now, we could listen
to our dialogue a third
time and I'm sure you
will understand everything.
I heard you were in a day last night.
So how did it go?
I went all the juicy details.
Um, well, actually.
We had a fantastic time last night.
He was amazing.
Okay.
Now, you really have to fill me in.
What's he like?
He's really good looking.
He's quite tall around 6-1.
He's in his early 30s and he's got
the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
He sounds hot.
What does he do for a living?
You know what?
This is the best part.
David is a junior investment
banker at Fortune Bank.
So he's got a great
career path ahead of him.
Hold on a sec.
His name is David.
Yeah.
That's my brother.
Okay.
So we looked at really
useful language for
describing people and
we want you to describe
your girlfriend, boyfriend or
even yourself or even yourself.
What do you look like?
How tall are you?
How old are you?
What is the language from today's lesson?
Right.
So come to EnglishPod.com and leave
your questions and comments on our website.
And your description.
And your descriptions.
Yep.
And we'll definitely be there
to answer any doubts as well.
Yes.
Well guys, thanks for listening today.
And until next time, goodbye.